Guide to the JoAnn Evansgardner and Gerald H.F. Gardner Papers, 1965-1991 AIS.2001.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Education Topics, VI.
  - Women's Studies Bibliography, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Female Education and PAAW Membership, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Women's Studies Fact Sheet, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Women's Thesis, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Guide to Female Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Syllabus Corrections, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Women's Studies Abstracts, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Women's Studies in Universities, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - International Associates of Women's Studies, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - National Women's Studies Association, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Alverno College, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Ecology of Women, DePaul University, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Focus Newsletter, Slippery Rock State College, 1978-1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - University of Illinois, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Sex and Sexuality Course, University of Pittsburgh, 1968-1969; 1976 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Women's Studies, University of Pittsburgh, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Yale University, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Educational Research, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Tobias Female Studies, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Women In Education Report, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Women's Education, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Symposium on Feminism, University of Pittsburgh, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Crisis: Women in Higher Education, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Female Economics and Education, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Education Status of Women, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Taskforce on Higher Education, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Women on Campus, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Characteristics of Doctorial Scientists and Engineers in the U.S., 1973 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - K-4 Guide, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Female High School Education, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Continuing Education, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Doctorate Recipients from U.S. Universities, 1967-1974 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Male and Female Activities, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Women's Role in Higher Education, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Action Methods Handbook, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Bowling Green State University, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Chatham College, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - City University of New York, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - University of Columbia, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Community College of Allegheny County, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Community College of Allegheny County, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Duquesne University, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania State University, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Point Park College, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Princeton University, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - San Diego State College, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - University of California-Berkley, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 08-09)
  - University of Chicago, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - University of West Virginia and University of Wisconsin, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Yale University, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - A.C.E., 1969 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Educational Lawsuits, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - HEW Fact Sheets, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Women's Education Reports, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Educational Equality, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Sex Role Stereotyping, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Affirmative Action, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Amendment Master, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Sexism in Education Report, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Higher Education Guidelines, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Sex Discrimination in Schools, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Higher Education-General, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Equal Rights Amendment at the University Level, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Victories Over Discrimination, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - American Association of University Women, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Sexism in Textbooks, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Gender Equality in Primary Education, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Elimination of Sexism Kit, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Pennsylvania Board of Education Kit, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Pennsylvania Higher Education and Pittsburgh School Board, 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 33-34)
  - Women's Educational Equality, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Duquesne University, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Harvard University, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Kalamazoo Public Schools, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Slippery Rock University, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Temple University, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - University of Bridgeport, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - University of Buffalo, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - University of Michigan, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - University of Minnesota, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Sports Clippings, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 46-47)
  - Sexism and Sports, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Title IX, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - NOW and Sports, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 01-02)
  - NOW Sports Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 03-04)
  - Pennsylvania NOW Sports Position, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - School Survey, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters Sent to Women's Sports Agencies, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Tag Day, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Pennsylvania Interscholastic Athletic Association, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 09-10)
  - Child Care Facilities, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Child Development, 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Child Education, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Childcare and Feminism, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Childcare Articles and Journals, 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Childcare Conference, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Children Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Children's Council, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Children's Lobby, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Children's March for Survival, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Daycare Dedication Committee, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Daycare Memos and Reports, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 22-23)
  - NOW Childcare, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Daycare Resources, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Dr. Harold Wren, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - NCEC Pamphlets, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - University of Pittsburgh Childcare, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - White House Conference for Children, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 29-30)
- Events and Organizations, VII.
  Series VII contains information on specific events and organizations in which Evansgardner and Gardner were affiliated or held an interest.
  Arrangement
  It is divided into five subseries:
  Subseries 1. Women's Political Caucus
  Subseries 2. Professional Women's Caucus
  Subseries 3. Chisholm for President
  Subseries 4. International Women's Year
  Subseries 5. Organizations
  - Women's Political Caucus, 1.
    - Bylaws, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - General Information, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Candidate Support Committee, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Delegate Selection, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Policy Council Meeting, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 07-08)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - State Caucus Organizing, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Information and Reports on Various Chapters, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
    - Recognition of State Caucus, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Organizing Committee, 1972, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Pennsylvania Women's Political Caucus, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Pennsylvania State Planning Meeting, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - National Women's Political Caucus of Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Mailing Lists, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Leader Times, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Illinois WPC, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Ohio WPC, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Texas WPC, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Virginia WPC, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Professional Women's Caucus, 2.
    The Professional Women's Caucus began as a conference at the New York University Law School on April 11, 1970; it was organized by Doris Sassower and JoAnn Evansgardner and was designed to represent women across professions. The theme of the conference was "Breaking Down the Barriers in the Professions" and presentations were given relating to women in the following professions: librarianship, engineering, health care, science, social work, and women's role in professional organizations. As a result of this conference involving more than 500 women from across the nation, the Professional Women's Caucus was formally established at a meeting held in Washington, D.C. in May of 1970. This series contains information about the original Professional Women's Conference and the resulting formation of the Professional Women's Caucus.
    - New York City Conference Agenda and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 25-26)
    - Mailers and Mailing Lists, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 01-03)
    - Chairperson, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Job Opportunities, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Doris Sassower Correspondence, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Kay Klotzberger Meeting Notes, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mailing Labels and Lists, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - NAACP Notes, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Speeches, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Meeting Reports, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Status Reports and Memos, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Executive Commission, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Membership, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - New York Caucus Meeting, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Merit Promotion Program, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Chisholm for President, 3.
    Shirley Chisholm, 1924-2005, was the first African American woman elected to Congress, representing New York's 12th district from 1969-1983. In 1972, she became both the first African American and the first woman to make a serious attempt to run for President of the United States. Evansgardner was Co-Chair of Volunteers for Shirley Chisholm and helped arrange rallies and events in the Pittsburgh area. The papers in this series are evidence of Evansgardner's involvement.
    - Chisholm Presidential Campaign in Pittsburgh, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Planning for Rally, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Position Papers, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
    - List of Supporters, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Pennsylvania Petition, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Clippings, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Letters, Notes, and Correspondence, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Photographs, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Progressive Woman, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - International Women's Year, 4.
    The United Nations designated 1975 International Women's Year in an effort to address the many issues facing women worldwide. In the US, Congress named the National Commission on the Observance of International Women's Year as the sponsor of 56 meetings held around the country in July, 1975. This undertaking resulted in studies, reports, and workshops on rape, insurance, the legal status of homemakers, wife abuse, and many other concerns. At the end of the year, representatives from each meeting met for the National Women's Conference in Houston, Texas, to compare notes and created a final report outlining problems and recommendations for change, which was submitted to President Carter and Congress in 1978. The documents in this series reflect all aspects of International Women's Year from preparation through follow-up meetings which occurred from 1972 to 1983. Records are arranged chronologically.
    - Mailing Lists, 1972-1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - IWY Commission, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Memos and Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - IWY Reports, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 04-06)
    - Continuing Committee, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - National Committee on the Observance of International Women's Year, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - State Officers, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Conference, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Houston, TX, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
    - Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box 19, Folder 13-14)
    - Copenhagen, DE, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Louisville, KY, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
    - Detroit, MI, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Organizations, 5.
    Women's groups provide support for female scientists, professionals, educators, and activists. Such groups can also contribute to a stronger presence for women within traditionally male-dominated professions or fields of study. This subseries contains information from a wide range of women's organizations and from civil rights groups with an interest in women's issues, 1971-1982. Files are arranged alphabetically by organization name.
    - Action for Children's Television, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - American Association of Speech and Hearing, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - American Association of University Women, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - American Philosophical Association on the Status of Women, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - American Sociological Association Sociologists for Women in Society, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Association of Feminist Consultants, 1972-1975 (Box 19, Folder 25-26)
    - Association of Women Mathematicians, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Association of Women in Science, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Association of Women Psychologists, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Black Caucus Papers, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Book Find Club, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Caucus for Political Science, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 04-05)
    - Citizens Advisory Council on the Status of Women, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Commission on Civil Rights, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Commission on the Status of Women, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Congress to Unite Women, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Federally Employed Women Conference, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Federation of Organizations for Professional Women, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Feminist Groups in Pittsburgh, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Fund for the Feminist Majority, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Gulf Oil Co., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - National Vocational Guidance, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - League of Women Voters, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - MLA Commission on Women, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - National Education Association, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - National Institute of Health, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - National Women' s Party, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - New University Conference, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 21-22)
    - NYC Commission on Human Rights, Alternatives to Layoffs, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Pennsylvania Commission on the Status of Women, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania Social Services Union, undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Pittsburgh Federal Executive Board, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 26-27)
    - Pittsburgh Women's Rights Conference, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - President's Commission on the Status of Women, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - San Francisco Sociologists for Women in Society, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Socialist Workers Party, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Sociologists for Women in Society, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - State Employment Committee, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - United Farm Workers, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - United Fund of Allegheny County, 1964-1973 (Box 20, Folder 35-36)
    - UFAC Employment Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - U.S. Mental Health Services, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - United Steelworkers, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Welfare Independent Neighborhood Groups, undated (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Women Against Pornography, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Women's Equality Action League, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Women in Anthropology, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Women in Community Service, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Women in the Historical Profession, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Women in Psychology, Mailing List, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Women in Physics, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Women in Science, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Women in Urban Crisis, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Women's Caucus on Modern Languages, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Women's Coordinating Council, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Women's Economic Conference, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Women's Health Conference, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Women's Information Service, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Women's Law Caucus, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Women's Liberation Movement, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Women's Religious Caucus, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Women's Rights Conference, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Women's Youth Conference, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Women Work Wonders, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Various Women's Organizations, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Workshops and Conferences, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
    - Correspondence with Women's Organizations, 1970-1972 (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Legal Topics, VIII.
  NOW was active at every level of government and worked to eliminate sex discrimination. The organization participated in demonstrations, court cases, and proffered advice when consulted. NOW was also in constant contact with local and federal agencies designed to enforce current antidiscrimination laws. In some instances NOW was simply involved to offer support, but remained active in as many ways as possible in order to help achieve equal rights for women.
  This series is divided into four subseries reflecting this involvement:
  Subseries 1. Equal Rights Act
  Subseries 2. Sex Discrimination in the Work Place
  Subseries 3. EEOC and PHRC
  Subseries 4. Other Legal Concerns
  - Equal Rights Act, 1.
    In 1923, the Equal Rights Act (ERA) was written by Alice Paul, head of the National Women's Party, and introduced into Congress by Senator Curtis and Representative Anthony later that year. The ERA was written in response to the 14th Amendment that granted equal rights to all men, but because of wording did not include women. It was reintroduced in every session of Congress from 1923 to 1970 and was buried or defeated every year. In 1971, the House of Representatives finally approved ERA without amendments, but the Senate did not approve it until 1972. Congress agreed to set an arbitrary time limit of seven years for ratification by the states. After much political action by NOW and other women's groups, the deadline for ratification was extended to June 30, 1982. On the deadline date, ERA was stopped three states short of ratification. Because these three states failed to ratify ERA there is no federal protection for equal rights, and the bill is currently reintroduced into Congress every year. This subseries includes information on the Equal Rights Amendment, 1968-1982. Materials included are briefings, positions and statements from legislators, testimonies, mailings and correspondence, publications, newsclippings, and information from campaigns and rallies attempting to extend the deadline for ratification.
    - House and Senate Votes, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - HJ Resolution 208, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Harrisburg Hearing Notes, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Amendment Analysis, 1976-1978 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - ERA Briefing, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Bayh Amendment, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Legal History, 1973-1975 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Illinois Laws and Legislators, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Division 35 and ERA, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - McGovern and ERA, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Names and Issues in senate, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - House Resolution 638, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Letters to State Congressmen, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Tally Sheet, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Senate Voting Records, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Letters From Legislators, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - ERA Extension Resolution, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence Between Legislators and NOW, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Bumpers Mailing, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Mailing Lists, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - ERA Congressional Remarks, 1970-1978 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Testimonies (Box 22, Folder 01-05)
    - John Mack Carter, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Norman Dorsen, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Catherine East, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Thomas Emerson, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Carol Forbes, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Paul Freund, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Fred Harris, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - S.I. Hayakawa (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Aileen Hernandez, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Leo Kanowitz, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Elizabeth Koonts, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Judith L. Laws, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Margery C. Leonard, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Ethel Ernest Murrell, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Ester Polen, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Marguerite Rawalt, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Bernice Sandler, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Other Testimonies, 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - ERA Supporters/Extension Boycotts, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Various Mailings, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 25-26)
    - Public Relations, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Support Correspondence, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Mailing Campaign, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - ERA and the Draft, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 30-31)
    - ERA Impact, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Matter of Justice and ERA, 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - ERA Ratification, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - National Now Efforts, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Recession, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - More Perfect Union, The Report of the National Commission on the Observance of International Women's Year, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - The Humanist, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - ERA Reports, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Media Campaign, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Issue Information, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Protective Laws, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - ERA State of Emergency, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Is ERA Necessary?, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - ERA Missionary Project, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - New York Times Magazine, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Passage and Ratification Clippings, 1970-1978 (Box 23, Folder 10-12)
    - Extension Clippings, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 13-14)
    - Editorials, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Articles, 1986-1987 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Position Papers, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Anti-ERA Information, 1973-1979 (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
    - APA Conventions and Campaigns, 1975-1978 (Box 23, Folder 20-21)
    - Citizens Advisory Council on the Status of Women, Bills of Special Interest to Women, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 22-23)
    - ERA and Catholics, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Council for Women's Rights, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Homemakers and ERA, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - KNOW and ERA, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Male VIP's, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - ERA and Mormons, 1979-1981 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Nebraska NOW (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - RA NOW YES (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - NOW and Politics, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - NOW ERA Countdown Campaign, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - State of Emergency Campaign, Washington, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 1)